Music playing.
Well, good morning, Canvas Community Church.
Working with a new mic set up this morning, so it might take a little bit for me to not sound like I'm underwater.
It's going to take even longer for me to look like I don't feel like I'm underwater.
I know it's been a heavy week for a lot of us, with many tragedies and the anniversary of one of the greatest tragedies of our nation kind of sitting with us.
And I, as a pastor, don't know that I can remember a time where I've ever felt as much angst and anticipation about what is going to come out of my mouth next.
And maybe I'm putting that on myself.
Maybe that's not from you.
Maybe that's from me.
Maybe that's not from the Holy Spirit.
Maybe that's from Satan.
I don't know.
But what I do know is I've been on social media and I have seen people say,
if your pastor doesn't say blank, you should leave the church.
And I've seen people say, if your pastor says blank, you should leave the church.
And I just don't think it's a coincidence that we find ourselves in a series about community and a specific message about community around a table centered on the broken body and shed blood of Jesus.
Because the reality is we live in a world where there are so many voices in our minds and in our hearts.
And we live in a consumer driven world where you are told if your pastor doesn't say the thing that somebody else on the internet that you've never met thinks they should say,
then you can just leave and go to another church.
And I am just here to pastorally remind you that the thing that Jesus created by breaking his body and shedding his blood was a community around a table.
And if you're waiting for me to say something in particular or waiting for me to not say something in particular so that you can have a reason to leave,
I just invite you to come to the table to have conversation because I'm not going to get it right every time.
And you're not going to get it right every time.
And if we create a culture where the moment we mess up, we get to leave one another's presence and form smaller communities,
that's the moment when we lose out on the family of God, mothers and fathers and brothers and sisters.
And so may we just work hard to cultivate a community here.
And it is hard work.
It will not be easy.
We will step on each other's toes.
We will kick each other in the shins.
But at the end of the day, we're family.
Around the table with Christ's broken body and shed blood at the center.
And if we gather for anything else other than that, may God himself close our doors.
So two things pastorally I want to share real quick before we hop into the message.
Just that I have been sitting with, and it's going to tie into the message.
It's really, it's crazy how God works in these ways.
But just two pastoral implications I want us to think through that I've seen happen on my social media feed,
in my text messages, all of the things that are happening.
And the first thing is this, that many of us live way too much of our lives on the Internet.
That we prioritize relationships with large groups of digital acquaintances
while forsaking real embodied relationships right in our community.
And so I think this is part of the problem.
We need to put our phones down and we need to be present with the people that God has placed in our lives.
Community.
Intentional community.
We need to spend our time in the right places and with the right people.
And I just, I think we're going to find out later that we weren't created to have
so many relationships with so many people that we've never seen and looked in the eye.
Like Marissa said, the eye is the lamp into the body.
If we can't look into somebody's eyes,
then we shouldn't be building our lives on a relationship with them.
Secondly, I think many of us have allowed a small minority of people with significant political power
to disciple us in the dehumanization of people we disagree with.
And that's all across the board.
People with significant power and interest in keeping that power have caused us to hate our brothers and sisters
who are in the same community as us, where we can't engage in conversation with them or look them in the eye.
And what is pressing forward in that is those people keeping power and us hating each other.
And we need to recapture the biblical vision that every human being is created in the image of God
and has tremendous value, dignity, and worth solely because of that fact.
We are image bearers of God.
And we need to see each other that way.
So we're over-investing in the wrong types of relationships
and we're putting our hope in the wrong place.
And hopefully today's message will give some biblical correction for both of those distorted realities
that I think all of us struggle with, myself included, to some degree or another.
Today, we are going to hop into week one of the four-week community series.
And I think it's helpful that we prioritize these relationships,
these face-to-face relationships around a table because we can lovingly correct each other.
And what we are striving for here at Canvas is multi-ethnic, multi-generational community around a table,
which means we will not all look at the same things in the world around us
and see them exactly the same way.
And we need to learn to have conversations with one another around a table
with Christ's broken body and shed blood at the center to remind us of what we're all about.
The best way to engage with these things is in community,
is not staring at me and forming opinions about what I'm saying,
but going together around a table with others.
And so we're intentionally launching small groups right now to do that.
There's some tables in the lobby with some new small groups that are going to be out there.
If you don't have a small group, you want to join a small group,
there's a couple of brand new ones, a Wednesday night one that's open to male and female,
a Wednesday night one that's ladies only, a Friday night one.
We've got young adult, we've got all kinds of small groups.
So find a place where you can fit in.
And it doesn't have to be a church small group.
Just grab a couple people from church and go out for coffee.
Do something together.
Be embodied in relationship with one another.
Okay, let me pray.
And then we'll do the thing.
Abba in heaven.
You are our good father.
And you have brought us together around a table.
You've made space for us.
You've made room for us.
To come with all of our fear, anger, and sadness and pain.
All of our doubt and disillusion.
All of our stuff.
Messy people.
God, and you've invited us to come to your table.
Not because we deserve it.
Not because we could ever earn it.
But because you have set a place for us at the table.
May we not lose sight of that invitation.
And God, may you do something supernatural in our midst today.
May you remind us that you have overcome the grave.
That there is no fear that we can give in to.
The worst thing that we could fear is death.
And you have conquered death in the grave.
There's nothing to fear.
God, remind us of that this morning.
For your glory.
For our good.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Well, many of you know that I was a youth pastor for a while.
And what that means in the American church is you have to learn how to play guitar.
You can't be a youth pastor and not know how to play the guitar.
It's just a problem.
And so I'm a guitar player, a very novice guitar player.
I enjoy playing guitar.
I played guitar a lot growing up in church.
I really enjoy everything except for keeping the guitar in tune.
It's a problem for me.
See, guitars are intentionally crafted for specific strings to be in tune to specific notes.
And when that happens, they play all together in harmony.
That happened.
You guys hear that?
I'm going to try not to forget.
It's not in tune.
Okay.
So when all the strings are tuned together, they play in harmony.
But no matter how good the guitar or how meticulous the guitar player, external factors are always going to pull those strings out of tune.
No matter how hard you try, no matter how hard you work, no matter how on top of it you are, eventually a string or two will find its way out of tune.
And then people like me are in deep, deep trouble.
Because I am what you would call pitch poor.
It's not tone deaf.
Pitch poor.
There's tone deaf and there's pitch poor.
And tone deaf people can't even tell the guitar is out of tune.
They just keep playing and singing and smiling because they don't know it's out of tune.
Pitch poor people can tell that it's out of tune but can't do anything to get it back into tune.
That's me.
I'm like, oh, my guitar is out of tune.
And I'm twisting and that's making it more out of tune.
And I'm like, well, that's not right.
But I don't know how to make it right.
I'm in trouble here.
And so I would often have to have somebody with good pitch help me get the guitar back in tune.
And that was helpful and good.
But I still always wanted to have the digital tuner to make sure it was, like, perfect.
Again, because I'm pitch poor.
And I trust the person with good pitch.
And I'm like, yeah, that sounds way better.
But, like, how right are they?
And so I would check it with the digital tuner.
And it was both the person with the good tune and the digital tuner that would
help me make sure that I could play my guitar in tune.
And I think in the same way as human beings, we were created for intimate community with
one another.
We were intended for our uniqueness to harmonize with one another according to God's good design.
But just like guitars, there are external factors that cause most of us to drift away from community and
and playing bad notes to the world around us.
And just like I needed somebody to come help me get my guitar back in tune.
We need one another in community to make sure that we are being the person that God has made us to be.
And even in that vision, as we come together and remind ourselves of who we're created to be, we're all prone to wander.
We're all prone to drift away.
And so we need what I would call communion, Christ's broken body and shed blood as that check, that digital tuner that's going to make sure you're like, yeah, we come together in community.
We remind ourselves of what's true.
We encourage one another to play the note that God's called us to play.
And then we put Christ Jesus at the center of the table to make sure that we do not drift away from who God's made us to be.
And so this morning, I want to spend most of my time talking about those two things, community and communion.
Community around the table, small group of people who are living life together, who are reminding each other of who God has called us to be.
And then just in case, because we're prone to wander, we get off track.
We keep Jesus at the center of the table.
We keep reminding ourselves of what this whole thing is about.
Because when we get together in community, we can easily drift away from God's vision for our life.
That's kind of the thesis for the rest of our time together.
Sound good?
We're going to be bouncing all over different Scriptures.
We're not going to have like one passage that we land in today.
And so let's just stick around for the ride.
All right?
First thing I want to look at is the creator's design.
Just like a guitar is created to play in tune with one another, human beings are created to live in community with one another.
Genesis chapter 1, verse 26.
Says, then God said, let us, notice the yellow words here, let us make mankind in our image, in our likeness, so that they together may rule over the fish in the sea and the birds in the sky, over the livestock and over the wild animals and over all creatures that move along the ground.
So God created mankind in his own image, in the image of God, he created, say it with me, them.
Male and female, he created them.
God blessed, say it with me, them, and said to them, be fruitful and increase in number, fill the earth and subdue it.
From the very first pages of Scripture, we see the doctrine that the church has called the Trinity, that God is one in three persons.
He says, let us create man in our image.
It's communal language.
God lovingly chooses to create us in his image.
And since his image is relational, us, let us make mankind in our image.
Since God's image is relational, that means that we are created as relational beings.
By nature, we are intended to live in community with one another.
Living in community is a necessary part of bearing the image of God to the world around us.
I love how Gary Brashears puts it.
He says, God is a family who makes family.
So what we see on the very first page of Scripture, let us make mankind in our image.
Put them together in community to rule the earth and subdue it.
God is a family who makes family.
Later on the first page of Scripture, we read God say, it is not good.
This is the first time we hear those words.
Everything is good.
And then we hear God say, it is not good.
What is not good?
It is not good for man to be alone.
So we see in God's design that we were made to live in community with one another, face-to-face, embodied relationships with one another.
It's part of who God is.
It's his very character.
It's his very nature.
And in order for us to image God, we have to live together in community.
And then the first thing he says is not good is that man is alone.
Healthy biblical community requires male and female relationship in order to image God.
We cannot image God alone.
And yes, part of this design is reproductive, which is a different sermon for a different day.
Part of it is fill the earth and subdue it.
But in other parts of Scripture, it's made clear that there are a number of reasons why singleness might be God's calling for individual,
which means as a church, we should be pursuing male and female relationships and communities that aren't just built on husband and wife.
Creating communities that are welcome spaces for married couples, singles, widows, and other unique situations.
Much of the American church culture has put the modern vision of the nuclear family as God's ideal, the center of God's design.
And that has left many people who don't neatly fit into that category feeling like they're on the outside looking in.
And what we've been invited to as brothers and sisters and mothers and fathers and aunts and uncles is a community around the table that includes people from all different situations and circumstances.
So from the first page of Scripture, we can see that to be fully human or to be in tune with the creator's design, we are to live in community with one another.
But from the second page of Scripture, doesn't take very long, right?
From the second page of Scripture, this in-tune instrument that God created begins to get pulled out of tune.
These are the obstacles that we face when it comes to creating community around the table.
And after this week, we all know there's no obstacles at all to creating unified community around the table.
Genesis 3.
When the woman saw the fruit of the tree was good for food and pleasing to the eyes and desirable for gaining wisdom, she took some and she ate it.
She also gave some to her husband.
Listen to this gentleman who was with her and he ate it.
Then the eyes of both of them were open and listen to this.
They realized they were naked.
So they sewed fig leaves together and made the coverings for themselves.
Then the man and his wife heard the sound of the Lord.
So the first thing they do is they hide parts of themselves from one another.
The second thing they do is they hide themselves from God.
The man and his wife heard the sound of the Lord walking in the garden in the cool of day and they hid from the Lord among the trees in the garden.
The man said, the woman you put here with me, she gave me some fruit for the tree and I ate it.
So can we see how from the very beginning pages of Scripture we begin to get out of tune with our design to live in vulnerable, transparent community with one another, self-giving, sacrificial love with one another?
Immediately between page one and page two, this is in tune instrument, page two, out of tune instrument.
That woman you gave me, I didn't ask for her.
I didn't need this, right?
I'm good on my own.
And here's the thing, when Adam sees Eve for the first time, naked right in front of him, does he say, I didn't ask for this?
No, he says, woman, bone of my bone, flesh of my flesh, thank you, Lord, for this good gift.
And then one page later, he says, I didn't ask for her, right?
And so there's these obstacles that immediately come into our lives that keep us from living into the vision that God has created us for, community around a table, tight-knit, close family, relationships with one another.
We were created for this thing.
But immediately shame comes in and we move away from one another.
We begin to hide parts of ourselves from one another and blame one another for the predicament that we find ourselves in.
Sound familiar?
This is on repeat throughout Scripture and now even in our day and age, we begin to hide parts of ourselves from one another and we blame each other for the predicament that we are in.
And we put on a false front, a self on social media that this is who I am.
And behind closed doors, we know that that's not fully true.
And we're not comfortable and safe enough to be who God made us to be in community with other people.
And so we create a false image for ourselves.
We cover ourselves up and we point in fingers and we blame shift about what the problem really is in creation.
And here's the heartbreaking part is the problem is sin.
The problem is sin.
Sin on the right, sin on the left, sin down the middle, sin in a different country.
It's sin.
The problem is sin.
And we create an image of ourselves that makes us more righteous than the other group of people that we have demonized.
And we make the problem no longer sin, but their sin.
This woman that you gave me.
It's their sin that's the problem.
It's not my problem.
It's their problem.
And the problem with that is it's all of our problem.
And we need God to intervene because apart from him, we cannot solve the problem.
Oh, boy.
Amen.
All of humanity has had significant obstacles to genuine community since the fall.
We can see it from the very beginning of Scripture.
But I think our current cultural moment creates some obstacles that are unique to us.
Some cultural concepts that weren't true in biblical times, but that are true now that make community even harder than it was in biblical times.
Like I said earlier, our culture has idealized the concept of the nuclear family, which is a relatively modern development in human history.
We've decided that the ideal biblical vision for the family is a mom and a dad and two and a half kids in a suburban house with a white picket fence.
Right?
Isn't this the vision that we have been taught?
That this is what God wants for you?
This is what God wants for everyone?
And the image of the ideal family structure has caused us to become even more isolated and internally focused.
Because when it's just four of us in this house behind a fence, then my life pursuit becomes providing for these four human beings and everybody else becomes an enemy and an obstacle to my joy.
And we were created for community with one another.
I'm not saying that the nuclear family is a bad thing.
I have a wife and a child and a dog and an invisible fence because I'm godly.
I don't want you to see that I don't want you.
It's not a bad thing.
I'm just saying it creates cultural obstacles because we isolate and we move further and further away from one another.
Amen.
When the biblical vision is that we would invite one another into community, but our culture has caused us to push each other further and further away.
We isolate and we hide behind our locked doors and we hide behind our glowing square rectangles.
And C.S. Lewis in his book, The Great Divorce, when he's artistically describing what hell is like, it's people moving further and further and further away from one another.
Because every time they're close enough to see somebody, that person rubs them the wrong way and they keep moving further and further away.
And C.S. Lewis says that's the vision of hell because we were created for community with one another.
And we culturally are doing this.
We're moving further and further away from one another.
We're isolating ourselves.
And we're investing in fake relationships with digital people that have no faces in front of them.
This is killing community.
It's killing God's vision that we should live together in harmony.
The image of the ideal family structures caused us to become even more isolated and internally focused than other times in history.
Our primary concern becomes making sure that our individual family has enough.
I'm going to step on a toe real quick and then move on, right?
On top of that, we invest incredible amounts of money and time, often going into debt and burning ourselves out to give our children whatever they ask for.
Even if the thing they ask for doesn't lead them to abundant life in Jesus.
So this is cultural, biblical problems that keep us from living in community.
And in contrast, the image we see in the Bible is culturally different.
And what I don't want to tell you, and I'm feeling, I'll get there.
I'm just, I'm always, I don't like creating tension, but sometimes you need to create tension.
So I'm going to put my, yeah, okay.
So in contrast to this image, when the Bible refers to family or household like we read in Ephesians this morning, it's not referring to the nuclear family.
It's not referring to one mom, one dad, and kids.
It's referring to a broader network of people that have decided to live in community together for the good of one another.
These are blood relatives and not blood relatives.
They have made an intentional decision to live in community with one another, to form a larger family unit, to pursue the common good for one another.
Now, don't freak out.
Were you freaking out?
Oh, okay.
That's good.
Don't freak out, because what I'm not saying is that you have to ditch the American cultural system and pattern your lives after first century Jewish family structure.
That would be a quick way to kill our church.
It's like, quit being 21st century Americans.
Let's all go back to first century Judaism, and it'll be great, right?
That's not the solution to our problem.
But I want to bring this up, because I think it's helpful for us to understand that when we read about family and about household and about community in the Scriptures,
what the Bible means by community and family is something very different than what we mean.
And because of this cultural framework, the early church would be held in the context of a household centered around the communion table.
Like, this is just the air that they're breathing.
When they go to church, they are going to church in their neighborhood, in somebody's house, right?
Like, this is the cultural framework that they have.
And now what we do is we drive 20 to 30 minutes away from our house to go to a church because we like the vibe, the cafe, the children's ministry, or the set list of the worship team.
We sit quietly in rows and center our time around one person giving a TED Talk for Jesus.
Here I am, and here you are.
And the moment that the person giving the TED Talk says something we disagree with,
or the moment when someone in leadership posts something on social media that we don't like,
we fire up the Google machine and we go looking for a different church.
This system is not created to help us cultivate genuine, authentic community with one another.
If anything, it works against it.
It keeps us busy and isolated, connected to a church organization, but not connected to the people who are the church.
Love how John Mark Homer puts it.
He says, for the first time in human history, you can go to church without ever experiencing community.
And so I just, I point all of this out to say, I think there are some external factors that are causing some of our guitar strings to go out of tune.
We're being pushed out of community and pushed into a fake version of community, and it's causing a lot of chaos in our lives.
And I just want us to notice it and lean into getting back in tune, sitting around a table with other people who are embodied human beings that live in our community,
that may or may not agree with everything that we think or believe about the Bible or politics,
but that we are seeking Jesus together, face-to-face, in real, genuine relationships.
So because these are the obstacles we're facing, we need to supplement Sunday morning church attendance with intentional pursuit of authentic community in smaller settings.
I'm not saying that this thing that we do here is bad.
It's not bad.
In many ways, it's a cultural, missiological expression of seeking to reach the church outside the walls of the gospel.
Because people are used to coming in and sitting in theater seating.
So we just said, hey, here's our theater seats.
Come sit down, we'll talk to you about Jesus, right?
It's not all bad.
All I'm saying is it's keeping us from fully experiencing the community that we were created for.
And this isn't easy or convenient, and it will take consistent sacrifice,
but I'm here to tell you from 10 plus years of experience of doing this thing that it's worth it.
Marissa and I had a small group in our house in Pennsylvania about, we probably met 49 weeks a year.
Literally, we took two or three weeks off.
And there were so many weeks that got to Wednesday night, and I looked at Marissa, and I said,
can we please cancel?
I don't want these people in my house.
I'm so tired.
I just want to turn on a TV and not be present with any human beings.
But we've made this decision with one another to live in community.
We'd agreed upon it.
And we kept pursuing it, even when it was hard.
And sometimes we'd all show up in sweatpants, and we'd all say, none of us want to be here.
And we'd all talk about what had happened in our weeks, and we'd pray together.
And now I haven't sat in that living room in five years, and if I pick up the phone and call any single one of those people,
they will answer it, and they will do whatever I need them to do, no matter what it costs them,
because we formed family around the table centered on Jesus, and it was not easy.
It took consistent sacrifice.
But, man, is it worth it.
And I know there are some of you in this room who I have sat in your living room consistently and regularly,
and if anything happened to me or my family, you guys would fight my actual family to provide for me and my family
before they got a chance to do it.
And it hasn't been easy.
Just had to look one of them in the eye.
Shoot.
They're family.
And that's what God invites us to do to become family around the table centered on the broken body and shed blood of Jesus.
Okay, sorry.
Now, we've pitched this series.
We've pitched this series as a series around the life and teachings of Jesus,
and we haven't talked about Jesus once yet from this avenue.
And so I want to look at Christ's example for how he modeled his life around community
and the invitation that he gave to his followers to come to the table.
Now, it wouldn't take you too long into a reading through the Gospels to see that Jesus prioritizes community with other people.
Like, we did a series on solitude.
There's times and places where God goes, where Jesus goes away from people.
But that's not the norm.
That's a spiritual rhythm that he had to stay connected to the Father,
but regularly he is with people, and regularly people are exhausting him.
Robert Karras puts it this way.
He has a commentary on Luke, and he says,
In Luke's Gospel, Jesus is either going to a meal, at a meal, or coming from a meal.
And now you know why I'm eager to follow this rabbi named Jesus.
Not only does he regularly model this for us, but he redefines what community actually is, what family actually is.
We talked about this last week, so I'm not going to spend a lot of time.
But his mother and sisters and brothers come looking for him, and people are like,
Hey, your nuclear family is out there.
They need to talk to you.
And he says, who is my mothers, my brothers, and my sisters?
He says, those.
He points to his disciples.
So he's in a room crowded, full of people.
His nuclear family is outside.
There's a crowd inside, and his disciples are around him.
And he points to his disciples.
And he says, those who do the will of my father are my mothers, and my brothers, and my sisters.
So family begins to be created for followers of Jesus around a table with Jesus at the center,
and our brothers and sisters becoming those who are surrendered to his example.
Does that make sense?
From the example of Christ, we can begin to draw out some practical principles.
Christ regularly invested in different sized communities at different levels.
And this is where I want to talk about where we get out of whack as human beings in the 21st century.
Jesus had his closest three disciples.
He had 12 disciples.
And he had a larger group of disciples, and then this massive group called the crowd.
And regularly and intentionally, he spent more and more time with the three and the 12 and the 70 to 120.
As things got closer and closer to the crucifixion, he was investing in these relationships.
I saw a meme not too long ago that was like, Jesus is a dude in his 30s, and he has three best friends.
And that's why I want to follow him, right?
Like how many of us have three best friends that we can call?
And like it takes investment.
It takes intentionality.
And these groups of people fit into a broader kind of social science category called Dunbar's Number.
And it's funny that Jesus kind of knows how humanity works.
And so social experts have said that human development, really, you can only have three, one to three very close friends.
And then you need a crew of about 12 to 15, and then a crew of about 120, and then relationships with the broader social network, right?
And this is what Jesus models for us.
But I think what has happened for us in our culture is we've flipped the numbers because social media exists.
And we spend so much time living our life in this digital world with this crowd of people.
We've invested an unnecessary number of hours in that.
And that has taken away from us investing time in the three and the 12 right around us.
And I wonder if that doesn't have something to do with some of the anxiety and fear that we're facing.
Because we're trying to have a relationship with thousands of people when we don't have a relationship with three to 12 people.
And we were created for intimate community with brothers and sisters and not trying to put on a face for a massive group of people, virtue signaling to them that we are what they are looking for.
It's all about belonging.
I see people from every side, every tribe, every category, and I see some of the things that they post.
And it's like a copy and paste script.
And what it is, it's us hiding.
It's us covering ourselves up and saying, please accept me.
I want to be on your tribe.
I want to be a part of your team.
I'm looking for belonging.
I'm trying to pursue belonging.
And at the end of the day, what we need is community around the table of Jesus.
And we all belong, but not because we have done anything or can do anything or will do anything to welcome ourselves at that table, but because Jesus has done it for us.
We're all looking for belonging, and we all have it freely at the table of Jesus.
Which leads me to Christ's invitation.
He gives his followers a regular invitation to keep coming back to this.
He knows that the world will pull them away.
He knows that there will be constant reasons to go out of tune with community.
He spent time with these dudes, a zealot and a tax collector.
He knows they're not going to want to have a meal together all the time.
He knows there's going to be some things going on in the world around them that would cause the zealot and the tax collector to be like, next week, bro, we're taking this week off.
I can't be eating around a table with you this week, right?
And he gives us this invitation to the zealot and the tax collector.
In Matthew 26, he says,
He said,
This is an invitation.
This is an invitation to all who would follow Jesus from this time forward,
that we would regularly lean into this meal around the table with brothers and sisters taking the broken body and the shed blood of Jesus to remind ourselves of why we are together in the first place.
Of why we belong and what it took to make us belong.
Because it's not that belonging didn't take effort.
It's that the belonging took the effort of Christ laying down his life for you and for me.
This is what makes us be able to sing that I have a seat at the table, that I can come to the table with all of my baggage, with all of my worries, with all of my fears, with all of my anger and frustration, with all of my sin.
And I can be welcomed and accepted because of the broken body and shed blood of Jesus.
And the early church immediately began to put this into practice.
They regularly met together in a large group and then from home to home, breaking bread together.
We read this in Acts chapter 2.
It's one of the reasons we try and schedule the bread and the cup as often as we can at the church.
Because the reality is, our band won't always play the songs that you like.
My message won't always be engaging or as engaging as you would like it to be.
There are things that will happen on Sunday mornings and they will not always happen the way that you want them to happen.
But if we take Christ's body and his blood and we partake in it, it's worth it.
Because that's what this whole thing is about.
This whole thing is about Jesus laying down his life to bring us into family with one another.
And it takes us receiving it.
Not everybody can stomach eating flesh and drinking blood.
Not all of us can, not all of us are willing to say, yeah, that first century Jewish rabbi was God in the flesh.
Who laid down his life for us.
So we receive it.
We build our lives around those who would receive it with us.
Creator's design was for us to live in community with one another.
That's how the guitar plays notes in tune.
Christ's example and his invitation is for us to fight back against the obstacles of sin and our culture
and lean into a community centered around the broken body and shed blood of Jesus.
And if we don't, we will quickly drift out of tune with who God made us to be and what he made us to do.
Community around a table with Christ's broken body and shed blood at the center.
Putting down our phones and investing in the right relationships.
And putting our hope in the right place.
Because there's lots of, there's lots of ideologies.
Lots of groups of people that are telling, that would tell you that if you put your hope in their thing.
That then you'll have peace and then you don't have to be afraid and then everybody gets abundant life.
And there's only one place that that's actually true.
So we've got to stop putting our hope in something other than Christ's body broken for us and his blood shed for us
because that is the only thing that will lead us to life and life everlasting.
So I'd encourage you to get in small groups.
I know this sounds like a 45 minute pitch to join a small group.
I don't care if it's one of our small groups.
Like sit around a table with brothers and sisters who agree with you and don't agree with you about a lot of things
but who all are willing to build their life on eating Christ's flesh and drinking his blood.
And if you are new to church, I am so sorry.
But that's what this thing's all about.
We believe that God is, that Jesus is the Son of God.
That he came to make a way for us to be restored to the Father.
That all of us have sinned and fallen short of God's glory.
We've all covered ourselves with shame and distanced ourselves from one another.
But Christ Jesus came.
To reconcile us back to the Father and bring us back into a right relationship with one another.
So if you're here and you're a follower of Jesus,
I'd love to invite you to eat Christ's body broken for you.
Drink Christ's blood shed for you.